Guide to the Pictorial Works Reference Collection, circa 1895-ongoing UA.01.11.0082
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Pictorial Works Reference collection
circa 1895-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0082
1 Linear Feet
In 1924, Trinity College was renamed Duke University and major construction on the university began and lasted until 1932. Since then, Duke University's campuses have undergone expansions and renovations that have led to several changes to the campus. The Pictorial Works Reference Collection contains files of printed materials that depict the Trinity College and Duke University campuses. This collection was compiled from various sources by the University Archives for reference and research.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Pictorial Works Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives from a variety of sources for use in reference and research and were received by the University Archives as gifts and transfers; UA2022-0055 was received as a gift from Greg Maletic in 2022.
Biographical / Historical
In 1892, Trinity College relocated to Durham from Randolph County, North Carolina. In 1924, the Duke Endowment was established to help develop the school into a university. That same year, Trinity College was renamed Duke University and major construction on the university began. This construction project consisted of expanding what is currently East Campus and building West Campus. In 1932, West Campus opened, and the Duke University Chapel was completed marking the end of the construction project. Since then, the campuses of Duke University have undergone expansions and renovations that have led to many changes to the campus over time.
Collection Overview
This collection consists of publications that feature photographs and drawings of the Trinity College and Duke University campuses along with descriptive text. The publications were sent to prospective students and used in publicity and fundraising.
College campuses; Duke University -- History; Duke University -- Buildings; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) -- History
- Trinity College, circa 1895-1913 (Box 1)
- Trinity College, circa 1914-1923 (Box 1)
- Trinity College panoramas, 1912-1913 (Box 1)
- Trinity College calendars, 1911-1913, 1915, 1920 (Box 1)
- Duke University, 1926 (Box 1)
- Alumni Register Pictorial Supplements, 1928, 1930 (Box 1)
- Duke University, 1929/30 (foldout) (Box 1)
- Duke University Durham, North Carolina, circa 1930 (Box 1)
- Bulletin of Duke University (pictorial), 1931-1958 (Box 1)
- Views of Duke University, 1932 (color artwork) (Box 1)
- Duke University (Illustrated) circa 1932 (Box 1)
- Duke University: A Reprint from Architecture, vol. 69, no. 3, 1934 March (Box 1)
- Campus Views, Duke University, circa 1936, 1938/39, 1941, 1943, 1947, 1948, 1952 (Box 1)
- Copper plate etchings of Duke University / Day Lowry, circa 1938/39 (Box 1)
- Duke: A Priceless Heritage, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
- Let us tell you about Duke University, circa 1954 (Box 1)
- Duke University, circa 1967, 1975, 2004 (Box 1)
- Sketches of Duke University / Charles H. Overly, undated [drawings] (Box 1)
- Trinity College brochures, loose pages, various years (Box 2)
- Trinity College, circa 1895-1913, copy 2 (Box 2)
- Trinity College, 1914-1923, copy 2 (Box 2)
- Trinity College calendars, 1912, copy 2 (Box 2)
- Duke University Pictorial Works, copy 2, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Duke University campus (aerial drawing), circa 1900 (Oversize-folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Print 101/2000
  Gift of Greg Maletic.